# **NATHAN HEMESATH**

1481 Parkside Commons Court, APT 300, Valley Park MO 63088

hemesath2@gmail.com (319) 429-4274

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

First and foremost, I am a self-starter. Learning new coding languages and techniques is something I enjoy on my free time. Through my variety of work experience, I've had the opportunity to discover that my passion lies in a field where I can work with a team to create a unique, exciting product for the client. I have the passion, motivation, and work ethic to be a great addition to a similarly motivated team.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Competencies:** Mobile responsive, site optimization, WCAG compliance, UI, Agile planning **Languages:** HTML5, CSS3, SASS/SCSS, JQuery, A/B Testing, Custom Email, RPL.

Familiar with

these languages: JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, SQL, AngularJS, Swift, ASP.Net.

**Software/Tools:** Adobe Dreamweaver, Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects, Animate CC, Node.is,

Xcode, Github, Wordpress, Bootstrap, Bitbucket/SourceTree.

**Databases:** MySQL, Firebase **Operating Systems:** Windows, macOS

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# New Balance, St. Louis, MO UI Web Developer

March 2017 - Present

- Coordinated with the site team each day to prioritize the board and ensure the proper tickets are completed in a timely manner.
- Identified ways to improve the tools we use each day to build content for the site.
- Collaborated with my team to bring on new innovations which not only improved the code base, but increased productivity throughout the whole site.
- Focused on growing our department with other teams, breaking down walls and bringing the team closer in a more collaborative way.
- Strengthened the backend for coding emails and utilized bulletproof methods to ensure all email clients are covered.
- Strived to maintain deadlines for other departments when they were in need of assistance.
- Aided in training new employees and contractors to bring them up to speed with our system.

*Environment:* HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, SCSS, SASS, Javascript, Photoshop, Responsive/Custom emails across all clients, A/B Testing.

# VGM Forbin, Waterloo, IA UI Web Developer

**January 2016 - March 2017** 

• Self-taught responsive web development to mobile optimize web sites.

- Collaborated with designers from different industry teams to interface for HME (Home Medical Equipment) Dealers, Banks, and even custom clients ranging from Bar/Grill Restaurants to fundraisers.
- Collaborated as part of the newly formed applications team in the early stages of future app development for the company.
- Translate the design team's vision into a WCAG compliant website while adhering to Aria for a complete user experience.
- Gained an understanding of the client's challenges while having attention to detail by working with client success to deploy updates correctly and ensuring additional errors or bugs were addressed ahead of launch.
- Participated in the planning and developing process for a more modular website template. Through
  this approach we reduced the need for interface work and allowed the designers to have a faster
  turnaround for building websites.
- Self-taught through online classes on how to incorporate smooth responsive animations to build a more interactive user experience.
- Integrated many custom forms and google maps for clients to reach new customers.
- Maintained browser compatibility for Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Edge, and IE8+.
- Focused on mobile responsive first when developing websites across all browsers for every platform.
- Introduced the use of SCSS to greatly improve the development process, which reduced the amount of time and resources used for future sites.
- Worked among a team each week utilizing the SCRUM agile process.

*Environment:* HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, SCSS, SASS, Javascript, PHP, .Net, Dreamweaver, Illustrator, Photoshop.

## VGM Homelink, Waterloo, IA Electro-medical Patient Care Coordinator

2013 - 2015

- Conveyed important information between insurance companies and the providers issuing supplies to their clients.
- Assisted patients in need of TENS/NMES units to help relieve pain and live a normal life.
- Exceeded production goals each month which allowed insurance adjusters to lighten their workload.
- Organized my work so each patient's order was placed on time to ensure they never ran out for the following month.
- Coordinated efforts between the patient and insurance adjuster to alleviate any questions or concerns that may arise.

Environment: Microsoft Word, Outlook,

## Target Food Distribution, Cedar Falls, IA Manual Warehouse Worker

2011 - 2013

- Organized a team of warehouse employees to efficiently perform daily tasks.
- Trained and directed new team members in different areas of the job, including proper lifting techniques, production quotas, and equipment training.
- Volunteered and contributed as part of the General Safety Team, addressing crucial risks and precautions.
- Assisted supervisors in directing team members when they had questions or concerns.

- Worked with QA(Quality Assurance) in addressing any health related concerns to maintain a healthy environment for the perishable produce.
- Provided my services to help IM(Inventory Management) when stock expired or inventory numbers reached undesirable levels.

Environment: Inventory Management, heavy duty equipment, manual labor

# **EDUCATION/TRAINING**

Hawkeye Community College, Waterloo, IA Associates in Web Programming and Development, 2016

University of Northern Iowa, Cedar Falls, IA B.S. in Criminology, 2011